[
    {
        "question": "يُؤْتِي",
        "answer": "gives",
        "pcklId": "532",
        "rootWordId": 12,
        "tlit": "yu'tī",
        "frequency": "549",
        "surahnum": "92",
        "ayahnum": "18",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " الَّذِي يُؤْتِي مَالَهُ يَتَزَكَّىٰ",
        "rootWord": "أ ت ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "آتَى",
        "waznEnglish": "to give",
        "waznTlit": "ātā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "لِأَحَدٍ",
        "answer": "for anyone",
        "pcklId": "71",
        "rootWordId": 20,
        "tlit": "li-aḥadin",
        "frequency": "85",
        "surahnum": "92",
        "ayahnum": "19",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَمَا لِأَحَدٍ عِنْدَهُ مِنْ نِعْمَةٍ تُجْزَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "أ ح د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَحَد",
        "waznEnglish": "one, anyone",
        "waznTlit": "aḥad",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "لَلْآخِرَةَ",
        "answer": "(is) the Hereafter",
        "pcklId": "155",
        "rootWordId": 22,
        "tlit": "lalākhirata",
        "frequency": "250",
        "surahnum": "92",
        "ayahnum": "13",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " وَإِنَّ لَنَا لَلْآخِرَةَ وَالْأُولَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "أ خ ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "آخِر",
        "waznEnglish": "Hereafter, end, last, later generations",
        "waznTlit": "ākhir",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "إِذَا",
        "answer": "when",
        "pcklId": "394",
        "rootWordId": 27,
        "tlit": "idhā",
        "frequency": "409",
        "surahnum": "92",
        "ayahnum": "1",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَاللَّيْلِ إِذَا يَغْشَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "إِذَا",
        "rootWordType": "nominal",
        "wazn": "إِذَا",
        "waznEnglish": "when",
        "waznTlit": "idhā",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Time adverb)"
    },
    {
        "question": "إِذَا",
        "answer": "when",
        "pcklId": "395",
        "rootWordId": 27,
        "tlit": "idhā",
        "frequency": "409",
        "surahnum": "92",
        "ayahnum": "2",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَالنَّهَارِ إِذَا تَجَلَّىٰ",
        "rootWord": "إِذَا",
        "rootWordType": "nominal",
        "wazn": "إِذَا",
        "waznEnglish": "when",
        "waznTlit": "idhā",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Time adverb)"
    },
    {
        "question": "إِذَا",
        "answer": "when",
        "pcklId": "396",
        "rootWordId": 27,
        "tlit": "idhā",
        "frequency": "409",
        "surahnum": "92",
        "ayahnum": "11",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " وَمَا يُغْنِي عَنْهُ مَالُهُ إِذَا تَرَدَّىٰ",
        "rootWord": "إِذَا",
        "rootWordType": "nominal",
        "wazn": "إِذَا",
        "waznEnglish": "when",
        "waznTlit": "idhā",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Time adverb)"
    },
    {
        "question": "إِلَّا",
        "answer": "except",
        "pcklId": "557",
        "rootWordId": 58,
        "tlit": "illā",
        "frequency": "663",
        "surahnum": "92",
        "ayahnum": "15",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " لَا يَصْلَاهَا إِلَّا الْأَشْقَى",
        "rootWord": "إِلَّا",
        "rootWordType": "particle",
        "wazn": "إِلَّا",
        "waznEnglish": "except",
        "waznTlit": "illā",
        "waznType": "Particle (Restriction particle)"
    },
    {
        "question": "إِلَّا",
        "answer": "Except",
        "pcklId": "657",
        "rootWordId": 58,
        "tlit": "illā",
        "frequency": "663",
        "surahnum": "92",
        "ayahnum": "20",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " إِلَّا ابْتِغَاءَ وَجْهِ رَبِّهِ الْأَعْلَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "إِلَّا",
        "rootWordType": "particle",
        "wazn": "إِلَّا",
        "waznEnglish": "except",
        "waznTlit": "illā",
        "waznType": "Particle (Exceptive particle)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الَّذِي",
        "answer": "The one who",
        "pcklId": "1422",
        "rootWordId": 59,
        "tlit": "alladhī",
        "frequency": "1464",
        "surahnum": "92",
        "ayahnum": "16",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " الَّذِي كَذَّبَ وَتَوَلَّىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ٱلَّذِى",
        "rootWordType": "nominal",
        "wazn": "ٱلَّذِى",
        "waznEnglish": "who, which, that",
        "waznTlit": "alladhī",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Relative pronoun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الَّذِي",
        "answer": "The one who",
        "pcklId": "1423",
        "rootWordId": 59,
        "tlit": "alladhī",
        "frequency": "1464",
        "surahnum": "92",
        "ayahnum": "18",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " الَّذِي يُؤْتِي مَالَهُ يَتَزَكَّىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ٱلَّذِى",
        "rootWordType": "nominal",
        "wazn": "ٱلَّذِى",
        "waznEnglish": "who, which, that",
        "waznTlit": "alladhī",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Relative pronoun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَأَمَّا",
        "answer": "Then as for",
        "pcklId": "37",
        "rootWordId": 73,
        "tlit": "fa-ammā",
        "frequency": "55",
        "surahnum": "92",
        "ayahnum": "5",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " فَأَمَّا مَنْ أَعْطَىٰ وَاتَّقَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "أَمَّا",
        "rootWordType": "particle",
        "wazn": "أَمَّا",
        "waznEnglish": "Then as for",
        "waznTlit": "ammā",
        "waznType": "Particle (Explanation particle)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَأَمَّا",
        "answer": "But as for",
        "pcklId": "38",
        "rootWordId": 73,
        "tlit": "wa-ammā",
        "frequency": "55",
        "surahnum": "92",
        "ayahnum": "8",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَأَمَّا مَنْ بَخِلَ وَاسْتَغْنَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "أَمَّا",
        "rootWordType": "particle",
        "wazn": "أَمَّا",
        "waznEnglish": "Then as for",
        "waznTlit": "ammā",
        "waznType": "Particle (Explanation particle)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَالْأُنْثَىٰ",
        "answer": "and the female",
        "pcklId": "23",
        "rootWordId": 77,
        "tlit": "wal-unthā",
        "frequency": "30",
        "surahnum": "92",
        "ayahnum": "3",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " وَمَا خَلَقَ الذَّكَرَ وَالْأُنْثَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "أ ن ث",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أُنثَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "and the female",
        "waznTlit": "unthā",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَالْأُولَىٰ",
        "answer": "and the first (life)",
        "pcklId": "59",
        "rootWordId": 85,
        "tlit": "wal-ūlā",
        "frequency": "170",
        "surahnum": "92",
        "ayahnum": "13",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " وَإِنَّ لَنَا لَلْآخِرَةَ وَالْأُولَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "أ و ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَوَّل",
        "waznEnglish": "(the) first",
        "waznTlit": "awwal",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "بَخِلَ",
        "answer": "withholds",
        "pcklId": "9",
        "rootWordId": 102,
        "tlit": "bakhila",
        "frequency": "12",
        "surahnum": "92",
        "ayahnum": "8",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " وَأَمَّا مَنْ بَخِلَ وَاسْتَغْنَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ب خ ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "بَخِلَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to be stingy, to withhold",
        "waznTlit": "bakhila",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "ابْتِغَاءَ",
        "answer": "seeking",
        "pcklId": "95",
        "rootWordId": 146,
        "tlit": "ib'tighāa",
        "frequency": "96",
        "surahnum": "92",
        "ayahnum": "20",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " إِلَّا ابْتِغَاءَ وَجْهِ رَبِّهِ الْأَعْلَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ب غ ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ٱبْتِغَآء",
        "waznEnglish": "they seek",
        "waznTlit": "ib'tighā",
        "waznType": "Verbal noun (form VIII)"
    },
    {
        "question": "تُجْزَىٰ",
        "answer": "to be recompensed",
        "pcklId": "72",
        "rootWordId": 245,
        "tlit": "tuj'zā",
        "frequency": "118",
        "surahnum": "92",
        "ayahnum": "19",
        "wordnum": "6",
        "arabicAyah": " وَمَا لِأَحَدٍ عِنْدَهُ مِنْ نِعْمَةٍ تُجْزَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ج ز ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "جَزَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to reward, to recompense",
        "waznTlit": "jazā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "تَجَلَّىٰ",
        "answer": "it shines in brightness",
        "pcklId": "1",
        "rootWordId": 257,
        "tlit": "tajallā",
        "frequency": "5",
        "surahnum": "92",
        "ayahnum": "2",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " وَالنَّهَارِ إِذَا تَجَلَّىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ج ل و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "تَجَلَّىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to reveal",
        "waznTlit": "tajallā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَسَيُجَنَّبُهَا",
        "answer": "But will be removed from it",
        "pcklId": "1",
        "rootWordId": 263,
        "tlit": "wasayujannabuhā",
        "frequency": "33",
        "surahnum": "92",
        "ayahnum": "17",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَسَيُجَنَّبُهَا الْأَتْقَى",
        "rootWord": "ج ن ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "يُجَنَّبُ",
        "waznEnglish": "to remove from",
        "waznTlit": "yujannabu",
        "waznType": "Verb (form II)"
    },
    {
        "question": "بِالْحُسْنَىٰ",
        "answer": "in the best",
        "pcklId": "105",
        "rootWordId": 321,
        "tlit": "bil-ḥus'nā",
        "frequency": "194",
        "surahnum": "92",
        "ayahnum": "6",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَصَدَّقَ بِالْحُسْنَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ح س ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "حُسْنَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "And excellent",
        "waznTlit": "ḥus'nā",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "بِالْحُسْنَىٰ",
        "answer": "the best",
        "pcklId": "106",
        "rootWordId": 321,
        "tlit": "bil-ḥus'nā",
        "frequency": "194",
        "surahnum": "92",
        "ayahnum": "9",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَكَذَّبَ بِالْحُسْنَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ح س ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "حُسْنَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "And excellent",
        "waznTlit": "ḥus'nā",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "خَلَقَ",
        "answer": "created",
        "pcklId": "179",
        "rootWordId": 431,
        "tlit": "khalaqa",
        "frequency": "261",
        "surahnum": "92",
        "ayahnum": "3",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَمَا خَلَقَ الذَّكَرَ وَالْأُنْثَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "خ ل ق",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "خَلَقَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to create",
        "waznTlit": "khalaqa",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الذَّكَرَ",
        "answer": "the male",
        "pcklId": "172",
        "rootWordId": 511,
        "tlit": "l-dhakara",
        "frequency": "292",
        "surahnum": "92",
        "ayahnum": "3",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " وَمَا خَلَقَ الذَّكَرَ وَالْأُنْثَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ذ ك ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ذَكَر",
        "waznEnglish": "Remember",
        "waznTlit": "dhakar",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "رَبِّهِ",
        "answer": "(of) his Lord",
        "pcklId": "955",
        "rootWordId": 524,
        "tlit": "rabbihi",
        "frequency": "980",
        "surahnum": "92",
        "ayahnum": "20",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " إِلَّا ابْتِغَاءَ وَجْهِ رَبِّهِ الْأَعْلَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ر ب ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَبّ",
        "waznEnglish": "the Lord",
        "waznTlit": "rabb",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "تَرَدَّىٰ",
        "answer": "he falls",
        "pcklId": "4",
        "rootWordId": 550,
        "tlit": "taraddā",
        "frequency": "6",
        "surahnum": "92",
        "ayahnum": "11",
        "wordnum": "6",
        "arabicAyah": " وَمَا يُغْنِي عَنْهُ مَالُهُ إِذَا تَرَدَّىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ر د ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "تَرَدَّىٰٓ",
        "waznEnglish": "to fall",
        "waznTlit": "taraddā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form V)"
    },
    {
        "question": "يَرْضَىٰ",
        "answer": "he will be pleased",
        "pcklId": "34",
        "rootWordId": 561,
        "tlit": "yarḍā",
        "frequency": "73",
        "surahnum": "92",
        "ayahnum": "21",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَسَوْفَ يَرْضَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ر ض و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَّضِىَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to be pleased",
        "waznTlit": "raḍiya",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "يَتَزَكَّىٰ",
        "answer": "(to) purify himself",
        "pcklId": "20",
        "rootWordId": 624,
        "tlit": "yatazakkā",
        "frequency": "59",
        "surahnum": "92",
        "ayahnum": "18",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " الَّذِي يُؤْتِي مَالَهُ يَتَزَكَّىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ز ك و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "تَزَكَّىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to purify",
        "waznTlit": "tazakkā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form V)"
    },
    {
        "question": "سَعْيَكُمْ",
        "answer": "your efforts",
        "pcklId": "29",
        "rootWordId": 692,
        "tlit": "saʿyakum",
        "frequency": "30",
        "surahnum": "92",
        "ayahnum": "4",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّ سَعْيَكُمْ لَشَتَّىٰ",
        "rootWord": "س ع ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "سَعْي",
        "waznEnglish": "and strives",
        "waznTlit": "saʿī",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "لَشَتَّىٰ",
        "answer": "(are) surely diverse",
        "pcklId": "3",
        "rootWordId": 755,
        "tlit": "lashattā",
        "frequency": "5",
        "surahnum": "92",
        "ayahnum": "4",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّ سَعْيَكُمْ لَشَتَّىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ش ت ت",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "شَتَّىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "separately",
        "waznTlit": "shattā",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْأَشْقَى",
        "answer": "the most wretched",
        "pcklId": "6",
        "rootWordId": 788,
        "tlit": "l-ashqā",
        "frequency": "12",
        "surahnum": "92",
        "ayahnum": "15",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " لَا يَصْلَاهَا إِلَّا الْأَشْقَى",
        "rootWord": "ش ق و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَشْقَى",
        "waznEnglish": "were wretched",
        "waznTlit": "ashqā",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَصَدَّقَ",
        "answer": "And believes",
        "pcklId": "24",
        "rootWordId": 830,
        "tlit": "waṣaddaqa",
        "frequency": "155",
        "surahnum": "92",
        "ayahnum": "6",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَصَدَّقَ بِالْحُسْنَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ص د ق",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "صَدَّقَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to accept truth, to admit, to confirm, to believe",
        "waznTlit": "ṣaddaqa",
        "waznType": "Verb (form II)"
    },
    {
        "question": "يَصْلَاهَا",
        "answer": "will burn (in) it",
        "pcklId": "11",
        "rootWordId": 858,
        "tlit": "yaṣlāhā",
        "frequency": "25",
        "surahnum": "92",
        "ayahnum": "15",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " لَا يَصْلَاهَا إِلَّا الْأَشْقَى",
        "rootWord": "ص ل ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "يَصْلَى",
        "waznEnglish": "to burn",
        "waznTlit": "yaṣlā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "لِلْعُسْرَىٰ",
        "answer": "towards [the] difficulty",
        "pcklId": "7",
        "rootWordId": 986,
        "tlit": "lil'ʿus'rā",
        "frequency": "12",
        "surahnum": "92",
        "ayahnum": "10",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " فَسَنُيَسِّرُهُ لِلْعُسْرَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ع س ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عُسْرَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "you disagree",
        "waznTlit": "ʿus'rā",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "أَعْطَىٰ",
        "answer": "gives",
        "pcklId": "6",
        "rootWordId": 1004,
        "tlit": "aʿṭā",
        "frequency": "14",
        "surahnum": "92",
        "ayahnum": "5",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " فَأَمَّا مَنْ أَعْطَىٰ وَاتَّقَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ع ط و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَعْطَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to give",
        "waznTlit": "aʿṭā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْأَعْلَىٰ",
        "answer": "the Most High",
        "pcklId": "39",
        "rootWordId": 1018,
        "tlit": "l-aʿlā",
        "frequency": "70",
        "surahnum": "92",
        "ayahnum": "20",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " إِلَّا ابْتِغَاءَ وَجْهِ رَبِّهِ الْأَعْلَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ع ل و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَعْلَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "and Exalted",
        "waznTlit": "aʿlā",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Adjective)"
    },
    {
        "question": "عِنْدَهُ",
        "answer": "with him",
        "pcklId": "158",
        "rootWordId": 1028,
        "tlit": "ʿindahu",
        "frequency": "201",
        "surahnum": "92",
        "ayahnum": "19",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " وَمَا لِأَحَدٍ عِنْدَهُ مِنْ نِعْمَةٍ تُجْزَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ع ن د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عِند",
        "waznEnglish": "with",
        "waznTlit": "ʿind",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Location adverb)"
    },
    {
        "question": "يَغْشَىٰ",
        "answer": "it covers",
        "pcklId": "12",
        "rootWordId": 1064,
        "tlit": "yaghshā",
        "frequency": "29",
        "surahnum": "92",
        "ayahnum": "1",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " وَاللَّيْلِ إِذَا يَغْشَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "غ ش و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "غَشِيَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to cover",
        "waznTlit": "ghashiya",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "يُغْنِي",
        "answer": "will avail",
        "pcklId": "42",
        "rootWordId": 1086,
        "tlit": "yugh'nī",
        "frequency": "73",
        "surahnum": "92",
        "ayahnum": "11",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَمَا يُغْنِي عَنْهُ مَالُهُ إِذَا تَرَدَّىٰ",
        "rootWord": "غ ن ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَغْنَتْ",
        "waznEnglish": "to avail, to enrich",
        "waznTlit": "aghnat",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَاسْتَغْنَىٰ",
        "answer": "and considers himself free from need",
        "pcklId": "45",
        "rootWordId": 1086,
        "tlit": "wa-is'taghnā",
        "frequency": "73",
        "surahnum": "92",
        "ayahnum": "8",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " وَأَمَّا مَنْ بَخِلَ وَاسْتَغْنَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "غ ن ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ٱسْتَغْنَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to be self",
        "waznTlit": "is'taghnā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form X)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَكَذَّبَ",
        "answer": "And denies",
        "pcklId": "182",
        "rootWordId": 1263,
        "tlit": "wakadhaba",
        "frequency": "282",
        "surahnum": "92",
        "ayahnum": "9",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَكَذَّبَ بِالْحُسْنَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ك ذ ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَذَّبَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to deny, to reject",
        "waznTlit": "kadhaba",
        "waznType": "Verb (form II)"
    },
    {
        "question": "كَذَّبَ",
        "answer": "denied",
        "pcklId": "183",
        "rootWordId": 1263,
        "tlit": "kadhaba",
        "frequency": "282",
        "surahnum": "92",
        "ayahnum": "16",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " الَّذِي كَذَّبَ وَتَوَلَّىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ك ذ ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَذَّبَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to deny, to reject",
        "waznTlit": "kadhaba",
        "waznType": "Verb (form II)"
    },
    {
        "question": "تَلَظَّىٰ",
        "answer": "blazing",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 1332,
        "tlit": "talaẓẓā",
        "frequency": "1",
        "surahnum": "92",
        "ayahnum": "14",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " فَأَنْذَرْتُكُمْ نَارًا تَلَظَّىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ل ظ ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ل ظ ي",
        "waznEnglish": "to blaze",
        "waznTlit": "lām ẓā yā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَاللَّيْلِ",
        "answer": "By the night",
        "pcklId": "80",
        "rootWordId": 1364,
        "tlit": "wa-al-layli",
        "frequency": "92",
        "surahnum": "92",
        "ayahnum": "1",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَاللَّيْلِ إِذَا يَغْشَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ل ي ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "لَيْل",
        "waznEnglish": "of the night",
        "waznTlit": "layl",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "مَالُهُ",
        "answer": "his wealth",
        "pcklId": "81",
        "rootWordId": 1427,
        "tlit": "māluhu",
        "frequency": "86",
        "surahnum": "92",
        "ayahnum": "11",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " وَمَا يُغْنِي عَنْهُ مَالُهُ إِذَا تَرَدَّىٰ",
        "rootWord": "م و ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "م و ل",
        "waznEnglish": "[the] wealth",
        "waznTlit": "mīm wāw lām",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "مَالَهُ",
        "answer": "his wealth",
        "pcklId": "82",
        "rootWordId": 1427,
        "tlit": "mālahu",
        "frequency": "86",
        "surahnum": "92",
        "ayahnum": "18",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " الَّذِي يُؤْتِي مَالَهُ يَتَزَكَّىٰ",
        "rootWord": "م و ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "م و ل",
        "waznEnglish": "[the] wealth",
        "waznTlit": "mīm wāw lām",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَأَنْذَرْتُكُمْ",
        "answer": "So I warn you",
        "pcklId": "47",
        "rootWordId": 1456,
        "tlit": "fa-andhartukum",
        "frequency": "130",
        "surahnum": "92",
        "ayahnum": "14",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " فَأَنْذَرْتُكُمْ نَارًا تَلَظَّىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ن ذ ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَنذَرَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to warn",
        "waznTlit": "andhara",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "نِعْمَةٍ",
        "answer": "favor",
        "pcklId": "118",
        "rootWordId": 1492,
        "tlit": "niʿ'matin",
        "frequency": "140",
        "surahnum": "92",
        "ayahnum": "19",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " وَمَا لِأَحَدٍ عِنْدَهُ مِنْ نِعْمَةٍ تُجْزَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ن ع م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "نِعْمَة",
        "waznEnglish": "then good",
        "waznTlit": "niʿ'mat",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَالنَّهَارِ",
        "answer": "And the day",
        "pcklId": "57",
        "rootWordId": 1525,
        "tlit": "wal-nahāri",
        "frequency": "113",
        "surahnum": "92",
        "ayahnum": "2",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَالنَّهَارِ إِذَا تَجَلَّىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ن ه ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "نَهَار",
        "waznEnglish": "repel them",
        "waznTlit": "nahār",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "نَارًا",
        "answer": "(of) a Fire",
        "pcklId": "140",
        "rootWordId": 1529,
        "tlit": "nāran",
        "frequency": "194",
        "surahnum": "92",
        "ayahnum": "14",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " فَأَنْذَرْتُكُمْ نَارًا تَلَظَّىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ن و ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "نَار",
        "waznEnglish": "a fire",
        "waznTlit": "nār",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "لَلْهُدَىٰ",
        "answer": "(is) the guidance",
        "pcklId": "274",
        "rootWordId": 1547,
        "tlit": "lalhudā",
        "frequency": "316",
        "surahnum": "92",
        "ayahnum": "12",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّ عَلَيْنَا لَلْهُدَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ه د ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "هُدًى",
        "waznEnglish": "Guide us",
        "waznTlit": "hudan",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَجْهِ",
        "answer": "(the) Countenance",
        "pcklId": "73",
        "rootWordId": 1592,
        "tlit": "wajhi",
        "frequency": "78",
        "surahnum": "92",
        "ayahnum": "20",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " إِلَّا ابْتِغَاءَ وَجْهِ رَبِّهِ الْأَعْلَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "و ج ه",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "وَجْه",
        "waznEnglish": "[I] have turned",
        "waznTlit": "wajh",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَاتَّقَىٰ",
        "answer": "and fears",
        "pcklId": "181",
        "rootWordId": 1641,
        "tlit": "wa-ittaqā",
        "frequency": "258",
        "surahnum": "92",
        "ayahnum": "5",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " فَأَمَّا مَنْ أَعْطَىٰ وَاتَّقَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "و ق ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ٱتَّقَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to be righteous, to fear (Allah)",
        "waznTlit": "ittaqā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form VIII)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْأَتْقَى",
        "answer": "the righteous",
        "pcklId": "183",
        "rootWordId": 1641,
        "tlit": "l-atqā",
        "frequency": "258",
        "surahnum": "92",
        "ayahnum": "17",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَسَيُجَنَّبُهَا الْأَتْقَى",
        "rootWord": "و ق ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَتْقَى",
        "waznEnglish": "and save us",
        "waznTlit": "atqā",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَتَوَلَّىٰ",
        "answer": "and turned away",
        "pcklId": "107",
        "rootWordId": 1648,
        "tlit": "watawallā",
        "frequency": "232",
        "surahnum": "92",
        "ayahnum": "16",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " الَّذِي كَذَّبَ وَتَوَلَّىٰ",
        "rootWord": "و ل ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "تَوَلَّىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to turn",
        "waznTlit": "tawallā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form V)"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَسَنُيَسِّرُهُ",
        "answer": "Then We will ease him",
        "pcklId": "9",
        "rootWordId": 1658,
        "tlit": "fasanuyassiruhu",
        "frequency": "44",
        "surahnum": "92",
        "ayahnum": "7",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " فَسَنُيَسِّرُهُ لِلْيُسْرَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ي س ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "يَسَّرَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to make easy",
        "waznTlit": "yassara",
        "waznType": "Verb (form II)"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَسَنُيَسِّرُهُ",
        "answer": "Then We will ease him",
        "pcklId": "10",
        "rootWordId": 1658,
        "tlit": "fasanuyassiruhu",
        "frequency": "44",
        "surahnum": "92",
        "ayahnum": "10",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " فَسَنُيَسِّرُهُ لِلْعُسْرَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ي س ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "يَسَّرَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to make easy",
        "waznTlit": "yassara",
        "waznType": "Verb (form II)"
    },
    {
        "question": "لِلْيُسْرَىٰ",
        "answer": "towards [the] ease",
        "pcklId": "27",
        "rootWordId": 1658,
        "tlit": "lil'yus'rā",
        "frequency": "44",
        "surahnum": "92",
        "ayahnum": "7",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " فَسَنُيَسِّرُهُ لِلْيُسْرَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ي س ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "يُسْرَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "We (have) made it easy",
        "waznTlit": "yus'rā",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    }
]